Nico Lauria

San Francisco, CA 916-627-5692 nicolauria@outlook.com www.linkedin.com/in/nico-lauria https://github.com/nicolauria

I've been working in the tech industry for the past five years. Spending time with developers sparked my interest in coding and I began to teach myself web development. I quickly developed a passion for coding and decided to pursue software development as a new career. After attending one of the top programming boot camps in San Francisco I am now in the process of finding a job. My skills include React, Redux and Rails among other technologies.

Skills

- Ruby
- JavaScript
- SQL

- Ruby on Rails
- HTML/CSS
- React.js

- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Git

Projects

Campfire https://campfire-chat.herokuapp.com

Campfire is a messaging application based off the popular chat app Slack. The app utilizes Rails action cable for web sockets and React Redux on the frontend.

Space Ninja https://nicolauria.github.io/space-ninja

Space Ninja is a computer game based off the popular arcade game Fruit Ninja. The game was built using Javascript and the P5 library.

Experience

OCT 2015 - AUG 2018

Operations Manager / Webmade, Sacramento CA

Manage new website builds using HTML/CSS and PHP. Oversee outbound/inbound sales process.

APR 2014 - OCT 2015

Account Executive / Guidebook, San Francisco CA

Handled customer facing relationships and business acquisition. Closed over \$500,000 in my first year.

Education

AUG 2018 - NOV 2018

2007 - 2012

App Academy / San Francisco

B.A. in History / UCLA